Sometimes it says Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī worships Sūrya.
Néha azt mondják, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī Sūryát imádja.
[Ultimate Nectar Extraction]
[A végső nektár kinyerése]
The famous yoga mantras mention, Guru Mahārāj said, Nārāyaṇ.
A híres jóga mantrák is említik, Guru Mahārāj is idézte, hogy Nārāyaṇ.
He quoted, and I don't have it committed to memory,
Nem emlékszem pontosan az idézetre.
He's the light of the light.
Ő a fények fénye.
When you look at the sun, it's divine illumination, actually—we know that.
Ahogy a napra nézünk, a fénye isteni ragyogás — ez mindannyian tudjuk.
It's divine. Sun-light is divine. It's obvious.
Isteni. A napfény isteni. Ez egyértelmű.
Every morning it's divine light.
Minden reggel isteni fény árad.
Nārāyaṇ is in the centre of the sun; the light of the light.
Nārāyaṇ a középpontja a napnak; ő a fények fénye.
That's how Guru Mahārāj described.
Valahogy így fejezte ki Guru Mahārāj.
So if we're fortunate to give some appreciation and go deeper …
Szóval ha elég szerencsések vagyunk, hogy megbecsüljük és elmélyüljünk ebben...
Sometimes Guru Mahārāj ...
Néha Guru Mahārāj...
Śri Puram means the city of Her … that She's illuminating.
Śri Puram az Ő [Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī] városa, amit bevilágít.
The heart of Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī is illuminating the whole spiritual existence,
Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī szíve bevilágítja az egész lelki világot,
and revealing Kṛṣṇa.
és felfedi Kṛṣṇát.
By the light of the sun we can see the Ghanaśyām; Śyāmasundar.
A nap fénye által vagyunk képesek meglátni a Ghanaśyāmot, Śyāmasundarát.
Like this afternoon's clouds here are Ghanaśyām-like clouds, revealed by sunlight.
Mint ahogy a ma délutáni, Ghanaśyām-szerű felhőket is a nap teszi láthatóvá.
There, Kṛṣṇa's steps are very soft and short. He's a cowherd boy.
Kṛṣṇa léptei nagyon finomak és aprók. Ő egy pásztorfiú.
Adbhuta-kram: 'He of wonderful stride and wonderful step.'
Adbhuta-krama: "Ő csodálatos léptekkel és lábnyommal rendelkezik."
Divine movement.
Isteni mozdulat.
Movement enhanced with beauty is dance.
A mozdulat átszőve szépséggel az maga a tánc.
The Kṛṣṇa movement is movement enhanced with beauty; dance.
Kṛṣṇa mozgása gyönyörű, áthatja a szépség, ez már tánc.
The Kṛṣṇa movement is the most beautiful movement,
Kṛṣṇa mozdulata a leggyönyörűbb mozdulat,
other than 'that Kṛṣṇa'.
több mint "csupán Kṛṣṇa."
Gāndharvikā—Gāndharvā Govindasundar— Srila Guru Mahārāj's deity, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī,
Gāndharvikā — Gāndharvā Govindasundar — Śrīla Guru Mahārāj murtija, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī,
she's dancing and singing, attracting the centre of all attraction; Kṛṣṇa.
táncol és énekel, ezzel vonzza azt, aki mindenkit vonz, magát Kṛṣṇát.
Kṛṣ-ṇa.
Kṛṣ-ṇa.
'Attracting', kṛṣir bhū-vācakaḥ śabdo (Cc: 2.9.30).
"Vonzó", kṛṣir bhū-vācakaḥ śabdo [Cc: 2.9.30].
Kṛṣṇa, 'attracting everyone to the centre,
Kṛṣṇa, "mindenkit a központ felé húz,
with His irresistible charm, beauty and sweetness';
az ellenállhatatlan bájával, szépségével és édességével";
Kṛṣ-ṇa, 'and then nourishing everyone'.
Kṛṣ-ṇa, "és aztán mindenkit táplál."
Hlādinī-śakti puṣṭi karan: Rādhārāṇī, extracting …
Hlādinī-śakti puṣṭi karan: Rādhārāṇī, képest kinyerni [a nektárt]...
It's great that Kṛṣṇa is Akhila-rasāmṛta-mūrti;
Csodálatos, hogy Kṛṣṇa maga Akhila-rasāmṛta-mūrti;
He's ecstasy personified.
Ő maga a megszemélyesített eksztázis.
But who can extract the nectar?
De ki képest kinyerni ezt a nektárt?
... need nectar extraction.
... szükség van a kinyerérésre.
So many things are like that, they have some ...
Sokféle dologra érvényes az, hogy van valami...
there's a method for how to extract.
van egy módszer, ahogy ki lehet vonni.
The method to extract the nectar of Kṛṣṇa is sevā, self-giving, self-offering.
Kṛṣṇa nektárjának kinyerésére a módszer a szolgálat, az önátadás, az önfelajánlás.